A Finding Aid to the Dimitri Hadzi Papers, 1910s-2007, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, 1957-2002; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 4.7 Linear feet Box 11-15
  - Selected Public Commissions, 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Bronze Doors (1966-1976), St. Paul Within-the-Walls Church, Rome, Italy, 1963-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5-8)
    - K 458 - The Hunt (1966), Lincoln Center, New York, New York, 1959-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
    - Thermopylae (1968), JFK Federal Office Building, Boston, Massachusetts, 1961-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 11-15)
    - Arcturus (1973), Federal Reserve Bank, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1969-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
    - Williamette River Oracle (1974), Oregon International Sculpture Symposium, Eugene, Oregon, 1972-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 18-20)
    - Williamette River Oracle (1974), Oregon International Sculpture Symposium, Eugene, Oregon, Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Oregon International Sculpture Symposium, Eugene, Oregon, Interview, 1974; Archival Resource Key; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - River Legend (1976), Federal Office Building, Portland, Oregon, 1974-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 3-6)
    - Portland and Eugene, Oregon, Mixed Photographs, 1974-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
    - Stone Atrium (1979), Johnson Wax, Racine, Wisconsin, 1978-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9-13)
    - Bishop's Triad (1980), Dallas Center, Dallas, Texas, 1978-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 14-15)
    - Propylaea (1982), Owens-Illinois, Toledo, Ohio, 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 16-19)
    - Propylaea (1982), Meeting, 1981; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Propylaea (1982), Owens-Illinois, Toledo, Ohio, Blueprints, 1980-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Pillars of Hercules III (1982), Stanford University, Palo Alto, California, 1978-1982, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
    - Atrium Sculpture (1984), Copley Place, Boston, Massachusetts, 1981-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 4-13)
    - Atrium Sculpture (1984), Copley Place, Meeting, 1982 September 29; Archival Resource Key; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Omphalos (1985), Harvard Square, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1981-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
    - Omphalos (1985), Harvard Square, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1981-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - Fox River Oracle (1986) Appleton, Wisconsin, 1981-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
    - Carleton Arch (1986), Carleton College, Northfield, Minnesota, 1984-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Primavera (1986), Pine Manor College, Chestnut Hill, Massachusetts, 1986-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Bronze (1989), Embarcadero Center West, San Francisco, California, 1989-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - agapetime (1990), Lowell, Massachusetts, 1987-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Red Mountain (1991), 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 11-14)
  - Other Commissions and Projects, 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence, invoices, photographs, publicity material, and blueprints from small-scale projects, recasted sculpture installations, and unexecuted projects. Correspondence, press releases, and notes related to Hadzi's original illustrations for Anothony Hecht's The Venetian Vespers (1979) and for the printing of Seamus Heaney's poem, Keeping Going (1993). Materials from Hadzi's role as set designer for John Eaton's opera Traveling with Gulliver (1997) include printed material, notes, sketches, correspondence, invoices, and some photographs. One folder composed of competition correspondence is found at the end of the series.
    - Chase Manhattan, New York, 1959, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - Omphalos III, Huron Towers, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1961-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - R.S. Reynold Memorial Award Sculpture, Virginia, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Thermopylae; Centaur, Princeton University, New Jersey, 1962-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Floating Helmets, Yale University, New Haven, Connecticut, 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 20-21)
    - Arcturus, Fullterton Junior College, Fullterton, California, 1973-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Crucifix, Pope John Paul II Visit, Boston, Massachusetts, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Sensebrenner Park Fountain, Columbus, Ohio, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Attiko Metro Project, Athens, Greece, 2003-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 25-26)
    - International Memorial at Auschwitz, 1957-1961, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Prudential Center, Boston, Massachusetts (unexecuted), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Munich, Germany (premiated but not executed), 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - University Center, Eastern Kentucky University, Kentucky (unexecuted), 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Commercial Union Assurance Company, Boston, Massachusetts (unexecuted), 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Bicentennial I-80 Sculpture Project, Lincoln, Nebraska (unexecuted), 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Rayovac, Madison, Wisconsin (unexecuted), 1992-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Art in Public Places, Vail, Colorado (unexecuted), 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Radcliff College Library, Cambridge, Massachusetts (unexecuted), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - The Venetian Vespers by Anthony Hecht, Etchings by Hadzi, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Keeping Going" by Seamus Heaney, Illustrations by Hadzi, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Travelling With Gulliver by John Eaton, Set Design by Hadzi, 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 14-15)
    - Correspondence, Commissions and Projects, 1973-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Potential Commissions and Projects, 1972-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Unexecuted Projects, Miscellaneous, 1959-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified Project Blueprints and Drawings, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Competitions, 1954-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Teaching Files, 1955-2000; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 12 Folders Box 15-16
  Files relating to Hadzi's career as professor of Visual and Environmental Studies at Harvard University include administrative correspondence, some exhibition material, clippings, lecture and discussion notes, course descriptions, communication with his students, and schedules. Also present is material related to potential employment opportunities; Hadzi's time as visiting instructor at the Vermont Studio School; artist in residence at Dartmouth College, and to various lectures given by Hadzi outside of Harvard.
  - Harvard University, Visual and Environmental Studies, Papers and Correspondence, 1975-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21-22)
  - Harvard University, Student Correspondence and Papers, 1976-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23-24)
  - Dreamstage: An Experimental Portrait of the Sleeping Brain (1977) Carpenter Center for the Visual Arts, Harvard University, 1977-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Harvard University, Learning from Performers Program, 1977-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University, Course Descriptions, 1978-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Dartmouth College, Artist in Residence, 1968-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Vermont Studio School, 1984-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Inquiries Regarding Teaching and Guest Artist Positions, 1955-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Letters of Recommendation, 1964-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lectures, 1976-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Museum and Gallery Files, 1947-2008; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1.8 Linear feet Box 16-17
  Files shed light on Hadzi's relationship with various galleries and museums in the United States and abroad. Material includes correspondence, loan and sale agreements, price lists, clippings, newsletters, shipping information, and some exhibition material.
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1959-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1968-1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Alpha Gallery, 1970-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Athens Gallery, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Charles Young Gallery, 1988-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Elaine Horwitch Galleries, 1977-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Gremillion Gallery, 1987-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
  - Gruenbaum Hallery, 1978-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
  - Guggenheim Museum, 1965, 1977-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Helene Seiferheld Gallery, 1960-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - HMK Fine Arts, Inc., 1978-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Ileana Tounta Contemporary Art Center, 1988-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Kouros Gallery, 1988-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
  - Landau Gallery, 1958-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Levinson Kane Gallery, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Lewis Newman Galleries, 1985-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Long Point Gallery, 1995-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 28-29)
  - Martha Jackson Gallery, 1956-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Meckler Gallery, 1974-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1959-2000, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1947-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Richard Gray Gallery, 1972-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5-6)
  - Rikugian Gallery, 1988-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Rosenthal Gallery, 1963-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8-10)
  - Ruth White Gallery, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Galleria Schnieder, 1956-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - St. Luke's Gallery, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Smith Anderson, 1971-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts, 1969-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Stephen Radich Gallery, 1957-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16-17)
  - Virginia Lynch Gallery, 1995-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Museums and Galleries, A-R, 1955-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Museums and Galleries, S-Z, 1956-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - College and University Galleries, 1957-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Galleries, Miscellaneous, 1957-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Museums, Miscellaneous, 1961-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Personal Business Records, 1949-2007; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Box 17-20
  Files relate to Hadzi's financial dealings, relations with foundries and material distributors, studio operations, and printmaking. Financial records include price lists, payments, inventories of art sold, loaned, or donated, and papers related to grants and fellowships from the American Academy in Rome, Louis Comfort Tiffany Foundation, and John Simon Guggenheim Foundation. Foundry and material files consist of Hadzi's correspondence, invoices, some photographs, and price lists. Studio operations are documented through bills, daily logs, phone messages, correspondence with assistance and students, and loose notes.
  - Art on Loan or Donated, 1971-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Business Notebook, 1965-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Collectors of Hadzi's Work, 1996, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1956-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, Accountant, 1965-1973, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Estimates, Stone and Bronze, 1978-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Financial, Prices, 1956-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Financial, Time Payments, circa 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Financial, Miscellaneous, 1963-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Foundries, Fonderia Artistica Bonvicini, 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Foundries, Founderia Arturo Bruni, 1961-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Foundries, Fonderia Nicci, 1954-1969, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Foundries, Mussi Artworks Foundry, 1991-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Foundries, Paul King Foundry, 1978-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12-13)
  - Foundries, Plycast Venturi Systems, 1973-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Foundry, Notebook, 1958-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Foundries, Miscellaneous Papers and Photographs, circa 1950s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 16-18)
  - Grants and Fellowships, American Academy in Rome, 1954-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 19-20)
  - Grants and Fellowships, American Academy in Rome, Conference, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Grants and Fellowships, John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, 1953-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Grants and Fellowships, Louis Comfort Tiffany Foundation, 1955-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Grants and Fellowships, 1949-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Material, New England Stone Industries, Inc., 1990-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Material, Providence Granite Co., Inc., 1979, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Print Making, Fox Graphics, 1985-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Print Making, Tamarind Lithography Workshop, Inc., 1960-1964, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Sale of Centaur with Pipes to Commune of Tilburg, Holland, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Sales, 1957-1959, 1969-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Sales, Inventories, Expenses, 1957-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Shipping Receipts, 1956-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Studio, Assistants and Students, 1971-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 3-5)
  - Studio, via Eleonora Pimentel, Rome, 1956-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Studio, Rome, Bills, Papers, Etc., circa 1960-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 7-9)
  - Studio, Charles Street, 1970s-1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Studio Log, 1975-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 11-21)
  - Rome and Cambridge,Mixed Studio Notes and Log, circa 1960s-1980s, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 22-24)
  - Studio Operations, 1960s-2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Studio Phone Messages, 1982-1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
  - Studio Visitor Sign-In Book, 1963-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 4-7)
  - Taxes, Inventory of Bronzes, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Visual Investments LTD., Artist Profiles, 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Printed Material, 1949-2007; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 3.7 Linear feet Box 20-24
  Clippings and articles contain stories about Hadzi, reviews of his work, and general publicity as well as some collected by Hadzi regarding other artists, books, history, geology, and music. Exhibition materials include announcements, posters, invitations, schedules, and some books. Also found in this series are post cards, invitiations, event ephemera, press releases, newsletters, and two books owned by Hadzi on Greek history and culture.
  - Bibliography, Articles, circa 1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Bibliography, Reference Cards (Photocopied), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Book Art, 1970s, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Book Publicity, 1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1952-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 14-20)
  - Clippings, 1980-2007, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 1-8)
  - Clippings, Book Reviews, 1976-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Greece, Italy, Japan, Germany, circa 1956-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Clippings, Other Artists, 1961-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Clippings, Visual Arts and Architecture, 1965-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, General, 1956-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 13-14)
  - Collections, 1965-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
  - Exhibition Material, 1949-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 21, Folder 17-18)
  - Exhibition Material, 1959-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 22, Folder 1-14)
  - Exhibition Material, 1967-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
  - Exhibition Material, 1978-2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 1-15)
  - Exhibition Material, "Exhibitions Visited During School Years", 1946-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Material, Other Artists, 1986, 1995-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - International Sculpture Conference, 1965-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Invitations, Special Events, and Programs, 1957-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 19-20)
  - Lecture Schedules and Calendars, 1970s-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 23, Folder 21-22)
  - Music Programs and Clipping, 1942-1977, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Postcards, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, Publicity and Exhibitions, 1951-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Millenial Afterlives: A Retrospective by Stratis Haviaras, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - History of Ancient Greece; Thesaurus of Greek Wisdom, 1989, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Photographs, circa 1930s-2006; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Box 24-25
  Snapshots, contact sheets, and negatives of Hadzi, his friends and family, exhibitions and events, projects and installations, foundries, and at his studios.
  - Portraits of Dimitri Hadzi, 1948-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Portraits of Dimitri Hadzi, Polaroids by Edwin Land, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Dimitri Hadzi with Family and Friends, circa 1930s-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Dimitri Hadzi with Family and Friends, Negatives, 1930s-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Dimitri Hadzi With His Art, 1950s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - New Talent (IX) (1956), Museum of Modern Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Venice Biennale, 1950s-1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Radich Exhibition, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Dimitri Hadzi: Sculptures (1963), 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Dusseldorf Exhibition, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Dartmouth Exhibition, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Dimitri Hadzi Sculpture: 15 Years in Rome, 1953-1968 (1968-1969), Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Seven Sculptors at Harvard (1983), Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Exhibitions and Events, Negatives and Contact Sheets, 1956-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Japan, circa 1960s, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Hadzi's Print Collection, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Projects, 1963-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Sculptures, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Sculptures, Small Bronzes, 1969-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Sculpture Installations, 1960s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Sculptures, Photographed by John Swope, 1969, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Photograph Album of Hadzi Sculptures, Text by Harry Cooper, circa 1997-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Sculptures and Drawings, circa 1940-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - Studio, Rome, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - Studio, United States, 1970s-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Other Artists, circa 1950s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - Other Artists, circa 1950s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Other Artists and Writers, Negatives and Contact Sheets, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Photographs by Frank Monaco, Negatives and Contact Sheets, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Contact Sheets and Negatives, Events, Art, Portraits, Installations, Studio, circa 1950s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6-8)
  - Negatives, Sculptures, Installations, Travel, Projects, Studio, 1951-1965, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
- Artwork, circa 1939-1998; Series 12; Archival Resource Key; 11 Folders Box 25
  This series includes six sketchbooks; several small drawings; one silhouette of Dimitri Hadzi from 1941; and one woodblock depicting a boudoir woman.
  - Hadzi Silhouette, 1941; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Faceless Man Drawing, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Loose Sketches, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Residential Drawings, circa 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbook, "Ceramics; Mosaics", 1982-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Sketchbooks, 1980-1998, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 16-20)
  - Woodblock of Boudoir Woman from Life, 1939, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 21)
- Audiovisual Material, 1952-2000; Series 13; Archival Resource Key; 12 Linear feet Box 26-40
  Documentary films and audio records, footage of events and exhibitions, project installations as well as scenes from foundries and in studios. The formats include VHS, U-Matic, Betacam, sound cassettes, and film reels.
  Also included in this series are transfer slips, notes, correspondence, budget details, and outlines pertaining to Hadzi's "JFK Film Project." Although most of the papers regarding the project date from the late 1990s, the project centered around Hadzi's Thermopylae installed in front of the JFK Federal Building in Boston, Massachusetts in 1968.
  - Documentaries, Archival Resource Key
    - Dimitri Hadzi Works in Black Wax, 1952; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 74)